The Carter Effect is a documentary film directed by Sean Menard.
In his latest documentary, Sean Menard gives viewers an unprecedented look at Vince Carter: the six-foot-six, eight-time NBA
All-Star from Daytona Beach who made waves in the Canadian basketball scene when he joined the Toronto Raptors in 1998.
Self, played by Vince Carter.
Self, played by Drake.
Self, played by David Stern.
Self, played by Tracy McGrady.
Self, played by Steve Nash.
Self, played by Charles Oakley.
The Carter Effect is a 2017 documentary film directed by Sean Menard.
It covers the impact of Vince Carter in Canada when he was still playing for the
Toronto Raptors of the National Basketball Association (NBA).
The film was shown at the 2017 Toronto International Film Festival and was
produced by LeBron James's digital video company, Uninterrupted.
Additionally, interviews of fellow NBA stars, former teammates, family members, and people associated with
the Toronto Raptors, combined with archival footage of Carter, were used throughout the movie.
Notable appearances in the film include his cousin Tracy McGrady, Canadian basketball star Steve
Nash, former NBA commissioner David Stern, and Toronto natives Director X and Drake.